Guide to the Records of the Ithaca College Study Center for Early Religious Life in Western New York,1978-1981.
Records of the Ithaca College Study Center for Early Religious Life in Western New York,1978-1981.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Records of the Ithaca College Study Center for Early Religious Life in Western New York, 1978-1981.
6000
Ithaca College Study Center for Early Religious Life in Western New York.
3.4 cubic ft.
Office files, lists of contact persons, record files, and field inventory files.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Office files, lists of contact persons, record files, and field inventory files of the Ithaca College Study Center for Early Religious Life in Western New York.
ORGANIZATIONAL HISTORY
The Study Center for Early Religious Life in Western New York compiled a series of collections of church and church-related records generated in the area of New York State known as the "burned-over district" due to the concentration of religious revivals there in the first half of the 19th century.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Office files, lists of contact persons, record files, and field inventory files of the Ithaca College Study Center for Early Religious Life in Western New York.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Ithaca College.
Subjects:
Religious institutions--New York (State).
Places:
New York (State)--Religion.; New York (State)--Religious life and customs.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
RELATED MATERIALS
See a listing of church collections that are part of this project here: http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/eguides/lists/churchlist1.htm.
See a listing of additional church collections here: http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/eguides/lists/churchlist2.htm.
CONTAINER LIST
- Internal Files
  - Paper by Judith Wellman- SUNY, Oswego (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - List of townships and counties (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Microfilming record (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Visiting researchers (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Catalog Authority List (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Restrictions forms (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Receipts (microfilming) (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Bills (microfilming) (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Future Possible Collections (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Original accessions sheets (with incomplete or inaccurate information) (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Photocopy of Accessions Log (6001-6081) (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Research inquiries (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence not related to research (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Paper by William Siles (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Report: March 1981 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - "Signposts on the Psychic Highway..." by Glenn Altschuler and Jan Salzgaber (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Paper by Sarah Lee (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Brackey-Siles correspondence (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Microfilm Copies Produced by the Study Center Housed Elsewhere (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Documents Located and Accessions by county (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - A non-manucsript donation (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Information on Millerism and Adventism (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Access and Reference Policy (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Receipts for negatives delivered to C.U. (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Descriptions of the Study Center Project (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Miscellaneous archival information (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Sarah Lee: talk re: Study Center (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Alphabetical listing of towns in western New York (incomplete) (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Alpha. List of townships and villages, by county (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Information on protestant denominations (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Information on "Annihilationism" (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - A history of the Baptists- Torbet (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Photocopy of 1827 document, "Confession of Faith" (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Article from the "American Archivists" (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Kathy Haynie: Notes for Speaking Engagements (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Paper: "Growth of the Church on the Northwestern Frontier" 1955 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - "The Upper New York Synod and its Origins" (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - "A Filing System for Historical Information" (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Examples from documents (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Miscellaneous histories (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Notes of collection descriptions (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Microfilm copies billing list (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Weekly reports - June 29-Sept. 30 1981 (Cont. below) (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Newspaper articles, related correspondence (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Historical Society Information (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - County lists of accessions (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Daily record of student hours (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Collections Grant Proposal (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Research Project Grant Proposal (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Annual Progress Reports (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Sample form letters (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Supply lists & info., reciepts (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Anti-Masonry in S.C. collections (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Calendars, field notes (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Budget: July-September, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - P.W. Description notes (summer ’81) (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Descriptions Progress Chart (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Church Information
  - Baptist Churches (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Congregational (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Episcopal (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Evangelical - United Brethren (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Free Methodist (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Friends (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Lutheran (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Mormons (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Presbyterian (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Roman Catholic (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Seventh Day Adventist (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - United Church of Christ (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - United Methodist (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Universalist (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Wesleyan Methodist (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Contact Records by County
  - Broome (Box 3)
  - Cayuga (Box 3)
  - Chemung (Box 3)
  - Chenango (Box 3)
  - Erie (Box 3)
  - Genesee (Box 3)
  - Livingston (Box 3)
  - Madison (Box 3)
  - Monroe (Box 3)
  - Montgomery (Box 3)
  - Oneida (Box 3)
  - Onondaga (Box 3)
  - Ontario (Box 3)
  - Oswego (Box 3)
  - St. Lawrence (Box 3)
  - Schuyler (Box 3)
  - Seneca (Box 3)
  - Steuben (Box 3)
  - Tioga (Box 3)
  - Tompkins (Box 3)
  - Wayne (Box 3-4)
  - Yates (Box 4)
  - -Unknown/Miscellaneous (Box 4)
- Field Inventories by County
  - Cayuga (Box 4)
  - Cortland (Box 4)
  - Chemung (Box 4)
  - Erie (Box 4)
  - Genesee (Box 4)
  - Livingston (Box 4)
  - Madison (Box 4)
  - Monroe (Box 4)
  - Onondaga (Box 4)
  - Ontario (Box 4)
  - Oswego (Box 4)
  - Schuyler (Box 4)
  - Seneca (Box 4)
  - Steuben (Box 4)
  - Tioga (Box 4)
  - Tompkins (Box 4)
  - Wayne (Box 4)
  - Wyoming (Box 4)
  - Field Inventories (Box 4)
  - Yates (Box 4)
  - Unknown/Miscellaneous (Box 4)
- Unprocessed Materials (Box 5)